hello everyone and welcome back to the
channel hey thank you so much for being
here if this is your very first time
here my name is fiddin Johnny and it's
my fiddle Channel and Magic product
review and before I do any magic product
review I always do a quick fiddle to so
sit back and enjoy I'm going to read a
little bit so I won't be looking right
at you hope you enjoy this is called the
green fields of france
d
[Music]
[Laughter]
la
[Applause]
[Music]
all right there you go the green fields
of france goes on much longer it's such
a lovely tune if you're not familiar
with it maybe I'll put a link to uh the
version down uh below uh but well worth
checking out and listening to anyway
anyway any R I'm glad you're here cuz I
have an interesting take today on a
review I'm reviewing
uh the shell game uh it's put together
by Myro and released through TCC magic
um I'm going to share what my experience
is with this product I hope it's helpful
for you so stick around and we'll get
right into
[Music]
it okay let's do this review it is the
shell game and it's manufactured by Myro
and released through TCC
magic okay so let me be blunt with you
here so this was sent to me by TCC magic
and every now and then you get products
that are sent to you and you love them
sent to you that you go like H I'm not
too sure about this one that's how I
felt about this one um and let me give
you some history so I think the three
shell game um for me at least as an
experience was something that I learned
as a kid very early on uh in magic with
uh some sort of usually plastic fake
Walnut shells uh and fake green peas at
least that was my experience and I
probably had it in multiple versions as
a kid um and it was okay um but wasn't
something I totally gravitated towards
so when I received this I I knew it was
a nice looking product um but I'm not
going to really like this probably that
much and it's going to be difficult to
do an inter uh uh a review when you
don't like it and it's been sent to you
but you know I just want to be
straightforward with you and what my
experience is I was so pleasantly
surprised by this and found myself
falling in love again with the three
shell uh game routine uh and this is
just a beautiful product and I'm not
saying it because it was sent to me uh
for free to do as a review to be honest
I was felt like I just didn't want to do
the review of this one because I didn't
think I was really going to like it
quite frankly not my sort of effect that
I would do and boy howdy was I wrong so
for those of you who don't know what the
uh shell game is uh historically it was
done with wall or at least that's my
experience like with wall nut shells
with a pee placed underneath it very
similar to three card Monte you would
put a a pee underneath the shell and
you'd move around the shells and you
supposed like keep an eye on it and you
would bet money on which shell uh the P
was under and of course spectator would
always
lose um and there's been multiple
variations of this done with multiple
different objects over the years this
one is done with uh a turtle shell or
tortoise shell um and done in brass and
wow it's beautiful and they provide for
you these uh two different colored uh
types of peas or balls that you use for
this routine so basically what's unique
about this it is still the three shell
routine except for it does include or
add the element of a color changing ball
to it so um let's get a little bit into
this in terms of first of all what do
you get so let me just open this for you
and you are going to
get these three shells now I'm going to
bring it up close to the camera here in
a second so that you can all see it so
you're going to get these uh three
turtle or tortoise uh shells they are
made from Pure brass um and they're
polished and look really nice you're
also going to get in a little bag here
you're going to get five little yellow
silicone uh balls or peas and you're
going to get three um
red cotton ball or made out of cotton uh
type balls um you're also going to get a
Vimeo tutorial that is 21 minutes in
length um so let's talk about how are
the instructions and I think this is
where I became sold which is ironic cuz
I often diss a little bit on TCC for
their tutorials cuz I often think oh
they're not the greatest totally wrong
on this one um it's not without some
sort of stuff like oh that could have
been better uh but the tutorial was
really good I don't know who did the
tutorial cuz you never see the face of
the person I don't know if it's my bro
or someone from TCC magic doesn't really
matter in the 21 minutes um you get a
focus on almost all on technique and
multiple techniques for stealing and
moving the pee or ball underneath uh
each of the different
shells and it goes into pretty great
detail detail on how to do that in the
21 minutes I found the different
techniques um
helpful more in depth than what I've had
probably historically and easy to do um
so I know some of you will care about
that part of it but pretty damn easy
some of them are a little bit um I would
say it's a little bit knacky at first
but with just minimal amount of practice
you will get what works for you in fact
I found that like when you do a steal
and I move um or push one of the shells
a little slow it doesn't work if I push
it faster works much better and I just
sort of had to play around with sort of
the movements to get it down so it
looked like really smooth for myself so
um it's shot really nicely um the my one
criticism on this while it does include
a single routine I felt like the routine
overall was almost an add-on because
most of it focuses on technique which is
important and really good um I think I
would have liked a more Fuller fleshed
out routine it's not that it was bad or
uh not good um but it felt like okay now
here's a routine now that you know the
technique and the truth is if you've
ever done the three shell game you know
that you can create a presentation that
works for you so I think that's what
they've done here is they put together
all the different techniques for
stealing and moving the piece without it
being uh noticed by your spectator and
then you can come up with putting
together routine uh and patter that's
going to work really good for you and I
think anyone who's working at this level
understands um that you have that skill
set and understanding to do that but I
would think for someone who's a little
bit newer they probably would have liked
maybe a little bit more fleshed out like
routine or maybe a couple different
presentation routines on how to do
it uh the instructions are done in
English easy to to follow um and really
good so let's talk about uh the gimmick
not really a gimmick it's really truly a
prop um so um here's what I would say
about the
prop they are freaking beautiful um you
can go to the web page and get like you
know how heavy they are I think they're
53 gram in weight they're solid brass
with a nice antique polish put on to
them they feel freaking great um um I
think of these fall into a category of
what I would call an heirloom prop of
magic that they're so nice and so
durable that they're the type of prop
you would pass on um after your death
not to get Grim or dark but they're an
heirloom like they're really beautiful
they're also the type of thing I think
for someone who's a collector man you
can proudly put these up on a shelf and
have them uh visible and they're just
really nice to look at even though
people may not even know exactly what
they um are so these will last several
lifetimes um they look professional if
you want to use these in a professional
gig they are at the highest level
quality and they uh scream you are a
professional uh magician um let me go a
little bit into some of the downside of
these well before I go to the downside
let me bring some of these up
all right I hope you can see that well
this is the
shell here's it's essentially designed
to look like a turtle shell or a toris
shell again it's
brass there are no magnets as part of
this if you're familiar like with the
cups and balls and you're new to the
shells there's no magnets or anything in
this these are designed to look like a
real um turtle shell um they're all
identical and look and they have a bit
of girth or wait to them there's a third
one I'm just showing you two of them
here let me show up close as well the
little
balls these are cotton the red ones and
the yellow ones are made of a
silicone so that's what they look like
let me go a little bit into sort of a
little bit of a downside or what I think
some folks might think of as a downside
from a prop
perspective because these are so
beautiful and made out of brass they're
a little bit heavier than what most
people might be used to when doing a
three shell routine um I know for myself
and I know others have done like walnuts
uh and that's mostly my history is done
with walnuts and people have done them
with real walnuts or walnuts made out of
plastic or sometimes 3D printed um and
they're a little lighter so sometimes
they're a little easier to pick up it
may take a little bit of practice for
some as you're doing a specific type of
Steel to lift them up and I say that
it's only true I think with one of the
Steels with the other Steels I didn't
have any problem sort of lifting up or
stealing it out um I found that when I
was first practicing and gripping it
with sort of hiding one of the peas it
was a little hard to hold on to but with
a little bit of practice I was able to
overcome it I do want to mention it
because that might be an issue that some
people say well I wish you had said that
like cuz I struggle like lifting up when
I do the specific steel um I just think
with a little more practice you'll get
it uh also I would add like if you have
dry hands it's probably a little bit
better if you have oily hands a little
more challenging because it can be a
little slippery they do talk in the
tutorial about having keeping your hands
nice and clean so they're not greasy uh
that type of thing they also talk about
keeping these uh little silicone balls
nice and clean because it works more
effectively if they're nice and clean um
so just keep them clean and they'll be
fine uh but I couldn't say enough nice
things about how beautiful these shells
are um it says that they're made from
solid brass they electroplated uh
surface with a hand edged and Polished
to give it an antique look now I'm
pulling that directly from uh the ad
copy U but for me it tracks yeah seems
true feel great
um let me talk about like so they
provide like five silicone balls and
three red balls you only need three
silicone balls uh for any of your
routines and maximum of the three red
balls they are simply extras for you in
case maybe you lose some of them so it's
nice that you've got in essence some
extra balls there if you want to so you
would probably use up to a maximum of
three balls at a
time
um I mentioned that you need to keep
them clean so that they work more
effectively let's talk about what is the
skill level I think this falls into ADV
Advanced beginner although it's
technically I think beginner I'll just
call it Advanced beginner but if you're
starting out magic I still think it
would be fine for you to make a purchase
of this uh as part of your magic journey
and you'll be happy even if it might
take a little bit more work uh and your
presentation might take a little bit
more work as opposed to if you're more
experienced but um it is definitely a
beginner level sort of skill set and one
of the reasons that it's included um
variations of it on in kid sets or at
least that was my experience growing up
I think for me as it comes down to skill
level I think of a lot of it just comes
down to practicing your
choreography I know that when as I was
practicing this at first I just look
clumsy even though I'm getting a steel
and returning it it just needed a
practice in choreography and getting the
fluidity of it down and then once you
have it down eventually you build up a
muscle memory and you no longer have to
think about it you're able to do it
automatic with it looking completely
natural without any sort of extra moves
where you're going like why did that
make that move that's not a natural move
and they do discuss that in the tutorial
which I really
appreciate so let me add like normally I
might talk about the pros and cons I'll
just talk about things I think you
should know
um I first started off going like this
really only works best on a performance
pad because that's how I was practicing
it now I know in the ad copy it says you
can do this on any surface and I thought
that's not probably really true I really
like it on this performance Pad but then
you know I went out and I really used it
on multiple different surfaces and I
found that it worked fine on a a regular
table with no tablecloth wooden table
found it worked fine on a plastic
tablecloth worked fine on a uh nice
white linen tablecloth uh I practice
with it on a um uh a marble surface
ended up having no problem so it sort of
went against what my initial gut was
like no this is really only on a
performance pad so I think I say that so
that you know that if you work in very
diverse sort of situations on different
performance um stages it works on all of
them I didn't have any problem suppose
if you're working on concrete maybe it
wouldn't work uh but I found basically
any flat surface it worked uh just
fine I could go on and on about how much
I love of these I think they're just a
beautiful prop and if you like the three
shell routine and you're looking for one
you'll like this um it's that
straightforward and it'll last a
lifetime and is an heirloom piece um I
think the folks who are going to like
this are performers who love the
classics of magic I think if you're a
street performer or Busker and you use a
a surface that you use it could be great
for busking on the streets um sort of
like a variation to the three card Monty
um close-up magicians will like this and
I think folks who are prop collectors
will like it as well now the uh cost of
this in the United States is $60 and I
think for something that is an heirloom
piece a very reasonable price um so you
can also though which reminds me because
I sometimes forget this I have one of
those discount codes uh at uh TCC magic
which is fiddlin Johnny and if you put
in my discount code fiddlin Johnny uh
you will get a discount and I'm not
always sure if it's applied to every
single purchase but when you go there
and you have a promo code just put it in
you will get a discount of I think up to
15% do I get some Kickback on the back
end yes I do it's usually something like
I think a dollar for
every1 or $10 it's not much it's
insignificant what I care about is that
you uh get the discount so I think over
time as people have used it I've got a
total of $10 so so I'm clearly becoming
rich off of the promo code uh so but I
want you to get the discount so go ahead
and use it at TCC magic all right that's
it um if you have this set or a
different set tell me your thoughts on
it uh and share that with the community
share your thoughts on cost and and what
you think about cost I know $60 some
folks might go like oh that's a bit much
um but for something that's heirloom
quality um I I think it's a reasonable
price um also make sure to hit that like
button And subscribe if you have not yet
done so it's free to do so and I
appreciate it all right thank you
everyone for being here I hope this was
a helpful review I'm fiddling Johnny and
remember to keep fiddling around with
your magic I'll see you all next time
bye-bye
[Music]
m